Guide to the Ivan Morris Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: 2003 Addition
  - Subseries VIII.5: Documents
    - Agreement with Kodansha International Ltd. for publication of The Genji Scroll, 2 Sept. 1969 (Box 45)
    - Contracts for publication of As I Crossed the Bridge of Dreams, 1970 (Box 45)
    - Agreement with Walter Verlag AG for the German publication of The Riverside Puzzles, 5 Jan. 1970 (Box 45)
    - Contract with Little, Brown and Company for the publication of The Lonely Monk and Other Puzzles, 5 Aug. 1970 (Box 45)
    - Agreement with Walter Verlag AG for German publication of The Riverside Puzzles and The Lonely Monk and Other Puzzles, 9 Nov. 1970 (Box 45)
    - Will and Testament of Annalita Alexander, 16 June 1976 (Box 45)
    - Announcement for Memorial Service for Ivan Morris, 17 Sept. 1976 (Box 45)
  - Subseries VIII.6: Photographs
    - Artwork, 1964, n.d. (Box 46)
    - Indentified People, n.d. (Box 46)
    - Japan, n.d. (Box 46)
    - Japan, n.d. (Box 681)
    - Morris, Ivan and Family, 1968, n.d. (Box 46)
    - Morris, Ivan and Family, n.d. (Box 681)
    - Morris, Ivan and Family, 1965, n.d. (Box 681)
    - Morris, Ivan and Family, n.d. (Box 681)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. n.d. (Box 681)
    - Unidentified People, 1923, n.d. (Box 46)
    - Unidentified Places, n.d. (Box 46)
    - Unidentified Portraits, n.d. (Box 681)
    - Unidentified Portraits, n.d. (Box 681)
    - Negative, n.d. (Box 46)
  - Subseries VIII.7: Audio Recordings
    Contents transcribed from label information provided on boxes for reel to reel audiotapes.
    - Act I backward, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 46)
    - Act III and blank; Gordon Cook, Blank and Sleeping Beauty, Act II, Blank for April 21, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 46)
    - Copia dell'intervista con la Signorina Annalita Marsigli, n.d., (5 inch reel ) (Box 46)
    - "The Fiction of Yasunari Kawabata," Oriental-Western Literary Relations Conference of MLA, 29 Dec. 1968, (7 inch reel ) (Box 46)
    - I Dig Love; Love, Ashe Puthli, n.d., (5 inch reel ) (Box 46)
    - Ivan Morris Memorial Service (DUB), Tracks A & B, 7 1/2 IPS, 16 Sept. 1976, (5 inch reel ) (Box 41)
    - Lee Graham Interview (Modern Japan) DUB, 29 Oct. 1975, (7 inch reel ) (Box 46)
    - "Nom" Theatre Tape Recording, Full Track Mono, 7 1/2 IPS, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - Novograd, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - The Pillow Book Part 2, Part 3 of 5, 7 1/2 IPS, Program 1 of 7; Net #PA 311-3-Teachers-Jacobson; Reel #2, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - The Pillow Book Part 3, Part 3 of 5, 7 1/2 IPS, Program 2 of 7-; Saltzman Telephone #1, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - The Pillow Book Part 4, Part 4 of 5, Program 4 of 7; Reel #4, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - The Pillow Book Part 5, Part 5 of 5, 7 1/2 IPS, Program 7 of 7; Reel #5, n.d., (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - Talk by I. M. at Asia House, Dec. 1967, (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - Talks re Waley, 1967, (7 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - [Unidentified], n.d., (5 inch reel ) (Box 47)
    - [Unidentified], n.d., (5 inch reel ) (Box 47)
  - Subseries VIII.8: Printed Materials
    - Amnesty International Articles, 1971-1975, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Ballet Program for Koma Ayako Ogawa Ballet Studio, 23 April 1973 (Box 48)
      [Program in Japanese]
    - "Be Careful" by Annalita, Jan. 1968 (Box 48)
    - Blank Postcards, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Book Reviews, 1969-1975, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Casino Card, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Congressional Record, Speech of Hon. Gale W. McGee on Academic Freedom, 27 July 1965 (Box 48)
    - Eulogies to Ivan Ira Morris, 1976 (Box 48)
    - Film Reviews, 1976 (Box 48)
    - Human Rights Newspaper Clippings, 1974-1977, n.d. (Box 48)
    - "The Iwakura Mission in Sweden" by Bert Edström, Working Paper 43, Oct. 1997 (Box 48)
    - "The Japanese Riots" from Notes of the Month, The World Today, Vol. 16, no. 7, July 1960 (Box 48)
    - Literature from the Foundation for New Educational Projects, 1977 (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1984, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Morris Family Newspaper Clippings, 1954-1956, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Program for Annual Commemoration Service at Columbia University, 20 Feb. 1977 (Box 48)
    - Resume for H. Clay Alexander, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Style Sheets, 1956-1966, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Tegami No Kakikata from Airyodu (publisher), 1968, (Text in Japanese) (Box 48)
    - Theater Program for "The Grinding Machine" by Annalita Alexander, 1978 (Box 48)
    - "The Tiger Cages of Con Son" from Winners and Losers by Gloria Emerson, Jan. 1977 (Box 48)
    - The Written Script, a novel by Annalita Marsigli, 1998 (Box 48)